https://easiconsult.com/privacy-policy/

1.800.922.EASI
contactus@easiconsult.com
E•A•S•I-Consult, LLC Privacy, Confidentiality and Disclosure Statement
Introduction
This policy outlines the effort of E•A•S•I-Consult, LLC to safeguard the privacy of your personal information
business
(e.g.,
administering
and
scoring questionnaires and assessments, conducting interviews, providing and developmental coaching). Any personal information gathered will be used for the sole purpose of E•A•S•I-Consult’s Human Capital consulting practices.
Individuals are entitled to privacy protection in all information systems under the custody and control
of
E•A•S•I-Consult.
While
there
is
no
completely
secure
method
of
storing
data
or transmitting information, specific precautions are taken, including: secure-socket layer protocols, encryption of sensitive customer data, etc. E•A•S•I-Consult will not be held responsible for any such loss, interception, or misuse of data prior to taking custody of personal information.
Data Collection
Information E•A•S•I-Consult collects
The following personal information may be required for E•A•S•I-Consult to conduct business with a customer:
First and last name
Email address
Position within organization
Organization/Company name
Phone number
Reponses to and scores of questionnaires and assessments
Demographic information
Note: Providing this data is not mandatory, but if it is not provided, E•A•S•I-Consult cannot move forward
with
providing
various
services
(e.g.,
creating
user
accounts,
setting
up
online questionnaires and assessments, creating developmental reports).
Certain information listed above, including information on job and test applicant demographics, may be provided by our Corporate Clients or other third parties.
Purposes for which we use personal data
To set up online assessments, assessment portals for customers, and user accounts on E•A•S•I-Consult’s assessment portal.
To improve our products and services that we provide to clients.
To
market
our
services
and
products
to
clients,
including
through
electronic
mail correspondence. This is only done in instances where it is in accordance with applicable law.
Carrying out the services agreed upon between the client and E•A•S•I-Consult, including, but not limited to, communications in relation to products or services received from us, handling customer requests, etc.
To learn more about customer preferences. We may look at the types of products and services you have used in the past to determine products you may interested in.
E•A•S•I-Consult
uses
aggregate
information
from
the
assessments
administered
to support validation efforts and create norm groups for use in E•A•S•I-Consult’s business for research or other scientific study. E•A•S•I-Consult does not use any personally identifiable data for such studies or research.
Data Access
Parties who have access to data and how the data is used
Authorized E•A•S•I-Consult Personnel have access to data. This is to ensure that we are able to provide excellent service to our clients.
E•A•S•I-Consult complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework principles outlined by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the processing, storage and collection of Personal Data transferred from a controller or processor regulated by EU data protection laws to the United States. The Privacy Shield principles deal with Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability (the “Privacy Shield Principles”). For more information on Privacy Shield and the Privacy Shield Principles, please visit http://www.privacyshield.gov/.
Corporate Clients:
E•A•S•I-Consult
shares
personal
data,
including
data
from
assessments
and
other
information about
you
with
our
corporate
clients.
Data
sharing
with
corporate
clients
occurs
if
you
employee
development program with this client. Personal data and exam information are not disclosed to unauthorized third parties or people, unless otherwise required by law.
We may disclose personal data, information from assessments, and other information to our sub- processors/suppliers for the purpose of providing the agreed upon services. In some instances, E•A•S•I-Consult may share personal data with suppliers who provide services to E•A•S•I-Consult, including
IT
and
cloud
providers,
communication
services,
testing/assessment
services
and printing providers. We strive to ensure that our providers take the necessary steps to protect personal data.
Law Enforcement/Public Authorities:
If required, we disclose personal data to public authorities, regulators or governmental bodies. Personal
data
may
be
disclosed
to
the
aforementioned
parties
when
these
parties
require disclosure, when we are legally obligated to disclose personal data to such parties, or when we believe, in our discretion, that disclosure is appropriate to protect our rights and interests or the rights and interests of third parties.
Data Retention
What documentation and/or data will be retained?
Paper
and
electronic
documentation
relevant
to
all
steps
conducted
during
E•A•S•I-Consult projects
will
be
retained.
These
documents
can
include
but
are
not
limited
to:
assessment calculations
and
scores,
assessment
reports,
interviews,
validation
analyses
and
data, competency models, assessment and selection system design notes, notes concerning decisions made during projects, and technical report documentation. In the case of there being two or more drafts of documentation or data analyses, the final version of this documentation will be the only version retained, provided that significant information is not lost by discarding previous document drafts.
How long will the documentation and/or data be retained?
Upon
completion
of
a
project,
E•A•S•I-Consult
will
retain
all
relevant
client
data
and documentation for a minimum of 3 years from the project completion date.
If the data and/or documentation are of specific legal importance (e.g., could potentially be used in a discrimination suit),
then
that
information
will
be
retained
for
at
statute
of limitation. In such situations, E•A•S•I-Consult will request expert legal advice for the retention of the documentation.
In what format and where will the documentation and/or data be retained?
All electronic documentation and/or data will be retained in the format (e.g., Word, Excel, SPSS) in which it was created and used during project completion. All non-electronic notes and paper documents
will
be
stored
in
organized
boxes
or
file
cabinets.
A
continuous
review
will
be conducted with the goal of converting all paper copies into electronic files.
All
final
version
electronic
data
files,
reports,
and
relevant
programs/presentations
will
be password protected and placed on a web-based shared folder, organized by year and by project. A review of stored information will be conducted approximately every 5 years to determine what documentation and/or data should be retained and what should be destroyed.
Confidentiality and Security
E•A•S•I-Consult uses a number of safeguards and processes to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure,
maintain
data
integrity,
and
ensure
the
appropriate
use
of
personal
data.
E•A•S•I-Consult
maintains
personal
data
and
data
from
assessments
on
secured
computers
and
all customers,
exam
candidates,
and
employer
accounts
are
password
protected.
E•A•S•I-Consult will take reasonable action to employ security measures designed to protect such information. No
personal
data
is
knowingly
disclosed
to
third
parties
except
as
described
herein.
No
data transmission over the Internet is guaranteed to be free of insecurities. Therefore, E•A•S•I-Consult cannot ensure the security of any information transmitted by users.
Notes
Client Policies
E•A•S•I-Consult
will
make
an
effort
to
use
clients’ personal data retention policies.
General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
Our commitment
E•A•S•I-Consult is committed to abiding by international regulations concerning data protection and
the
General
Data
Protection
Regulation
is
part
of
that
commitment.
Customers
in
the European Union can be assured that their data is being securely used by E•A•S•I-Consult and that full compliance of the GDPR is in effect.
Legal Basis for Collecting Data
E•A•S•I-Consult’s legal basis for collecting customer data is given through consent by the customer to have their data processed for the specific purposes of assessment, employee development and human capital consulting.
Rights Guaranteed by GDPR
Right
to
be
informed
–
Customers
have
how
their personally identifiable information is being used.
Right to access – Customers have the right to know what information is held about them and the way it is processed.
Right
of
rectification
–
Customers
have
the
right
it
is inaccurate or incomplete.
Right to erasure – Customers have the right to demand personal data be deleted without a specific reason being required for deletion.
Right
to
restrict
processing
–
Customers
have
the
right
to
block
processing
of
their personal data.
Right to data portability – Customers have the right to retain and reuse their personal data for their own purpose.
Right to object – Customers have the right to object to their personal data being used in certain circumstances.
Right of automated decision making and profiling – Customers have the right to demand their data not be used in an automated decision-making process (i.e., one without human intervention).
Contact Information
Any questions concerning E•A•S•I-Consult’s privacy policy should be directed to assessments@easiconsult.com or +1.314.209.9495.
Customers may contact E•A•S•I-Consult at any time to:
Request access to information that E•A•S•I-Consult has concerning the individual
Correct any information that E•A•S•I-Consult has about the customer
Delete any information that E•A•S•I-Consult has about the customer
Informed Consent
E•A•S•I-Consult
requires
informed
consent
from
customers
before
acquiring
any
personal information for the purpose of completing any assessment/questionnaire. Below is a sample of an informed consent statement.
E•A•S•I-Consult’s Informed Consent
By participating in this assessment, developmental activity or human capital consulting initiative I
acknowledge
that
I
have
reviewed
E•A•S•I-Consult’s
Privacy,
Confidentiality,
and
Disclosure Statement and I am willing to offer informed consent based on the following:
I have been made aware of:
With whom my information will be shared,
What specific information will be shared,
The purpose of sharing the information,
How the information will be used.
I consent to offering information to E•A•S•I-Consult for the purposes of the
above-mentioned activities. I consent to allow E•A•S•I-Consult to share my information with their client organization for
the
purposes
of
making
talent
management
decisions
(e.g.,
hiring
decisions,
succession planning,
individual
development,
etc.).
I
recognize
that
I
may
not
be
given
access
to
all information gathered (e.g., testing content or results) as such disclosure could compromise the security of the test or assessment process or prejudice the use of results of particular tests.
Expert Advocates in Selection International, LLC – d.b.a. – E•A•S•I-Consult®
